

TOBIAS ECHENIQUE PODESTA

tobiasechenique@gmail.com Mendoza, Argentina github.com/tobieche110 linkedin.com/in/tobiasechenique

UNIVERSITY TECHNICIAN IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Born in 2001. I am a **Software Developer** and a fourth-year student pursuing a **Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Software Development** at Universidad de Aconcagua, Mendoza, Argentina. I obtained its intermediate degree, **University Technician in Software Development**, in 2024. I have work experience as a Functional Analyst, utilizing Agile methodologies (such as SCRUM), and as a freelance developer, working with Java Spring Boot and React JS. Additionally, I have numerous personal and university projects using other languages and frameworks, such as Python, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, PHP, among others.

SKILLS AND LANGUAGES

English - Advanced (C1) Spanish - Native Python Java (Spring Boot) React

React HTML, CSS, Javascript

C#

PHP SQL

Ruby on Rails Flow Diagrams

SCRUM

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OpenDev Pro Functional Analyst

January 2024 - April 2024

Responsible for engaging with the client to develop functional requirements. My tasks included:

- Utilization of Jira Software for the creation of user stories.
- Development of representative flow diagrams of the development to be carried out.
- Development of **data mappings** for integrations between applications.

Freelance

December 2023 - January 2024

Full Stack Developer for freelance projects

Management Software for India & Co:

- React JS for frontend (Tailwind CSS).
- Java Spring Boot for backend (Spring Security, JWT Token, Restful API).
- Documentation writing, Agile methodologies, MySQL for relational databases.

Eventbrite

November 2018 - November 2018

Educational Internship

I had the opportunity to do an educational internship in this renowned company with my school. I learned basic Python and agile methodologies, specifically, Scrum.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics and Software Development — Universidad del Aconcagua, Mendoza March 2022 - Present

- I obtained the intermediate degree of University Technician in Software Development in 2024.
- First exposure to Web Development (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP).
- I learned Java and Object-Oriented Programming in general.
- I learned SQL database management (MySQL).
- I learned how to develop and write research projects.
- I learned about agile methodologies and project management.

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science — Universidad de Cuyo, Mendoza March 2019 - November 2021 (Incomplete)

- I learned Python and basic programming. I programmed my own libraries for HashTable, LinkedList, Tree structures, and others.
- I learned advanced mathematics (algebra, mathematical analysis, analytic geometry).

PROJECTS

<u>algoritmo-paneles-acusticos</u> — Research project for CONAIISI 2023

In college, I had to develop a research project. This is about an application that detects the early reflections in a room for professional music production purposes and displays the results with an overhead view of the room. It is programmed in Python. This project was selected to participate in the 11th National Congress of Computer Engineering / Information Systems (CONAIISI), which took place on November 2nd and 3rd, 2023.

Compra Skater 2 — Final project for "Autómatas y Lenguajes", Universidad del Aconcagua 2023

Made with Ruby on Rails. It is an extension and port of my former project "Compra Skater". It features more functionalities and all the advantages that Rails offer, like the MVC model.

<u>Virtual Library</u> — Final project for Algorithms and Data Structures 2, Universidad de Cuyo 2021

This project consisted in using my own Hash Tables library to make a program that can search words between text files and sort them for relevance. It was all programmed using Python.